Guide to the Cornwall Recreation Collection 1848-1998 MS 028 MS 028 MS 028
Cornwall Historical Society
Cornwall Recreation Collection
1848-1998
Cornwall Historical Society
Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941
MS 028
0.5 linear feet (1 box)
This collection contains information related to recreation in Cornwall.
Provenance
This collection is comprised of miscellaneous documents initially collected by town historian E.C. Starr, and added onto by subsequent scholars and members of the Cornwall Historical Society.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
This collection contains information related to recreation in Cornwall during the period of 1848-1998.
Scope and Content Note
The material in this collection concerning social gatherings, both local, national and international levels, experienced by Cornwall residents, as well as sporting events and the performing arts are all included in this collection. This collection is comprised of miscellaneous documents initially collected by town historian E.C. Starr, and added onto by subsequent scholars and members of the Cornwall Historical Society.
The collection is divided into three sections, namely Social Gatherings, Sporting Events, and the Performing Arts, and organized chronologically within those sections.
Arrangement
Folders are arranged type of recreation then chronologically within each type of recreation.
The files are grouped into 3 series:
Social Gatherings
Sporting Events
Performing Arts
Cornwall (Conn.)--history.; Cornwall (Conn.); programs (documents); Starr, Edward C. (Edward Comfort), 1844-1941; Cornwall Historical Society
- Social Gatherings
  - Program for South Cornwall Independence Day Exercises, 1848 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Souvenir from l’Exposition Universelle, Paris, 1889 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Columbian Exposition closing speeches booklet, 1892 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Invitation to Cornwall Bridge “social hop", 1905 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Article on Cornwall historic house tour, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notice for Dwight Place Seminary Young Ladies Retreat, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sporting Events
  - Article about Sedgwick Institute football team, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Article, “Cornwall Team Wins Contest,” about first aid meet, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Article, “Litchfield County Makes Strong Bid for Skiing Trade", 1947 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Article, “Mohawk Ski Area Expands for Winter Sport", 1948 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Constitution of Cornwall Base Ball Club, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Performing Arts
  - Program for “Henry’s Wedding", 1890 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Program for “108th Anniversary of Washington’s Birthday", 1900 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Program for “The Creation,” by the Cornwall Chorus, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Program for spring pageant, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Program for “Home Ties", 1922 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Program/ticket for “A Pageant of Colonial Connecticut", 1935 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Program for “The Male Animal,” by the Cornwall Players, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Program for “The Cornwall Talent Show,", 1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Program for “Post Road,” by the Cornwall Players, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Program for “Her Step Husband,” by the Masquers, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Program for play performed in Cornwall by Canaan High School senior class, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Announcement of public reading by Tom Walker, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)